Caresir Gonzales

Rosharon, TX 77583

Phone: 832-349-1105 | Email: caresir@yahoo.com LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/caresir-gonzales GitHub: https://github.com/Caresir | Hacker Rank: https://github.com/Caresir | Hacker Rank: https://www.hackerrank.com/caresir | Hacker Rank: <a href="mailto:https://www.hackerrank.com/caresir-nt/mailto:https://www.hackerrank.com/caresir-nt/mailto:https://www.hackerrank.com/caresir-nt/mailto:https://www.hackerrank.com/caresir-nt/mailto:https://www.hackerrank.com/caresir-nt/mailto:https://www.hackerrank.com/caresir-nt/mailto:https://www.hackerrank.com/caresir-nt/mailto:https://www.hackerrank.com/caresir-nt/mailto:https://www.hackerrank.com/caresir-nt/mailto:https://www.hackerrank.com/caresir-nt/mailto:https://www.hackerrank.com/caresir-nt/mailto:https://www.hackerrank.com/caresir-nt/mailto:https://www.hackerrank.com/caresir-nt/mailt

SUMMARY

Licensed Mathematics (4-8), Generalist (EC-6), SPED (EC-12) teacher with extensive years of measuring student mastery of standards, formulating individualized intervention plans and improving student achievement. Obtained a Master of Mathematics Education with 10+ years of professional experience in a fast-paced environment utilizing various blended learning models. Aiming to leverage advanced knowledge of training methodology with strong data analytical, problem-solving, organizational, writing, and communication skills to optimizing both student and school success. Competent in technology presentation programs and databases.

SKILLS

Tools: Google Suite, Adobe Photoshop, Microsoft Excel, Microsoft Word, PowerPoint, Python, Pandas,

Numpy, Jupiter Notebook, Excel, TEAMS and SAS

Data Management Systems: School City, PostgreSQL, Azure, SQL, and AWS

EXPERIENCE

Master Teacher/ Intervention Data Analyst DeSoto ISD Ruby Young P-STEAM Academy

2021- 2022 DeSoto, TX

Met with administrators on a consistent basis to discuss campus goals and plans. Provided one-on-one peer coaching to mentee teachers in the development of data-driven lesson planning and classroom management. Provided valuable feedback to teachers for improving teaching practices and enhancing parent and student relationships. Compiled data related to student achievement to identify causes and implement research-based interventions to increase student success. Conducted academic advising sessions with students to discuss their growth and progress throughout the school year.

Mathematics Department Chair/Teacher Houston ISD Attucks MS

2018– 2020 Houston, TX

Lead and coordinated professional development and Professional Learning Communities (PLC's) as the math department chair. Used critical thinking skills to formulate strategic plans for the mathematics department based on students' data. Communicated and discussed data and student performance during presentations with administrators, parents, teachers, and specialists. Computed and analyzed student data, using statistical formulas in excel and progress monitoring tools in OnTrack to ensure student success. Conducted research for professional development in mathematics, blended learning models, and designated supports. Developed and designed the intervention and core math curriculum for sixth, seventh, and eighth grades.

Key Accomplishments:

- Lead the development and design of the intervention and core math curriculum for sixth, seventh, and eighth grades based on the TEKS analyst reports and incorporating a blended learning model. This curriculum boosted the number of students passing the math STAAR by 30% which helped the school increase.
- Developed and presented the "Intervention Plan for STAAR" a 6-week long intervention curriculum directly correlated STAAR review plan based on the identified student data profiles to prepare students for success on the STAAR test.

SPED Case Manager/Teacher Plano ISD Otto MS

2015– 2018

Plano, TX
Accomplished in using data in SAS (education analytical suite) to develop and write Individual Education
Plans (IEP), guide classroom instruction, and enhance student achievement. Proven ability to maintain
multiple case history records and prepare IEP reports. Responsible for presenting caseload reports
during ARD meetings with parents, administrators, specialists, and students. During PLCs, used data
visualization to foster a data-driven culture and deep discussion around action plans. Coordinated efforts

Key Accomplishments:

• Developed and designed the BLAST intervention math curriculum in seventh and eighth grades which increased student success rate by 11%.

with co-teachers to utilize best teaching practices in blended learning models. Sixth, seventh, and

• Developed and presented the "countdown to the STAAR" curriculum 8-week plan based on the students' individual data profiles to prepare students for success on the STAR test.

STEM Mathematics Algebra Teacher Houston ISD Attucks MS

eighth-grade math teacher and Track and Field coach.

2012-2015

Houston, TX

Collaborated with administrators, parents, students, and specialists to build data literacy to meet the campus instructional goals. GT testing coordinator, student council coordinator, Math curriculum developer, and program recruiter. Provided data-driven instruction that increased student achievement and engagement. Utilized student data analysts to plan and prepare classroom instruction and assessments.

Key Accomplishments:

- Recognized for well above, the most effective teacher for academic growth by EVAAS. Recorded teachers gain-index of 3.78-grade levels.
- Demonstrated good judgment in the use of best instructional practices including blended learning.

Mathematics Teacher Universal Academy

2010-2012

Irving, TX

Seventh and Eighth Grade Mathematics Teacher. Summer Enrichment Teacher. Assistant Track Coach. Elementary Social Studies Teacher (5-6) and filled in as a substitute teacher (K-12) when needed.

EDUCATION

Fintech Bootcamp Certificate: Rice University, Houston, TX

11/2020

A 24-week accelerated program focused on expanding technical programming abilities in Amazon Web Services (AWS), Python 3, NoSQL, Big Data, Ethereum, Blockchain, and Machine Learning.

Master of Mathematics Education: Western Governors University, Houston, TX 05/2020 For my capstone paper, I conducted research on successfully integrating technology into the classroom through a professional development framework. Blended learning is a style of teaching that incorporates a blend of technology and face-to-face instruction. With thorough research, I created a two-week professional development training framework to address multiple areas of teacher concerns when implementing a blended learning environment.

Bachelor of Arts in Psychology: University of Houston, Houston, TX